{
    "id": "a7caca96ed1149e1b9c66e8aca13d666",
    "title": "Gerunds or Infinitives | Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He insisted ……………… paid at once.",
            "description": "After a verb + preposition, we normally use the –ing form of the following verb.",
            "answers": [
                "on being",
                "on to be",
                "to be"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "967fe67e9b684811bc74d4b9cf1b8a4d"
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t like the idea ………………….. old.",
            "description": "After a noun + preposition, we usually use the –ing form of the following verb.",
            "answers": [
                "to get",
                "of getting",
                "to get"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "7ed3d6a6726c4b37b34f0861a174f380"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am not very good …………………..",
            "description": "After an adjective + preposition, we usually use the –ing form of the following verb.",
            "answers": [
                "to dance",
                "at dancing",
                "in dancing"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "12276042491840e7b7452e94f53f87b6"
        },
        {
            "question": "I was interested .....................… that my ancestors were from Burma.",
            "description": "We use an infinitive after learn to talk about successfully learning something. ",
            "answers": [
                "in learning",
                "to learn",
                "to learning"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c84060a2d1894697a1b03e2f0319f75a"
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t think they mean ………………….. for the moment.",
            "description": "When ‘mean’ means ‘intend’, it is followed by an infinitive.",
            "answers": [
                "getting married",
                "to get married",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "006b2bd4639b41928b92a5c2470ac42c"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you want to pass the test that will mean …………………. hard.",
            "description": "When ‘mean’ means ‘involve’, it is followed by an –ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "to work",
                "working",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "537764ac112b4bc98ab38663aadc537e"
        },
        {
            "question": "I’m beginning ………………… things better.",
            "description": "Infinitives are preferred after continuous forms of begin and start.",
            "answers": [
                "understanding",
                "to understand",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "dd336d8d1f5c4c9fb06c198628fdf184"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am not accustomed …………………. alone.",
            "description": "After ‘be accustomed to’, we can use an infinitive or an –ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "to live",
                "to living",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "d97575a4187748a1b662cbe4f4cb9984"
        },
        {
            "question": "We are still waiting for them ……………..",
            "description": "Some verbs are followed by for + object + infinitive. Wait is one of them. An –ing form is not usually possible in these cases. ",
            "answers": [
                "arriving",
                "to arrive",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "243abefed59343a9821c5bbbc7d4a969"
        },
        {
            "question": "They are talking about ………………… to the country.",
            "description": "We use an –ing form after a preposition.",
            "answers": [
                "to move",
                "moving",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "83bbab2c9cc3477e8575154e0fc7a538"
        },
        {
            "question": "They repaired the roof instead ………………… on holiday.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "to go",
                "of going",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "07a0fbcef2744384a9119bc312884326"
        },
        {
            "question": "I regret ……………….. my job. It was a big mistake.",
            "description": "We use an -ing form after regret to refer to the past.",
            "answers": [
                "to quit",
                "quitting",
                "to quitting"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "a33fce420e6445d79d4855fa90185de2"
        }
    ]
}